《非常小特务3》
水叮当就像在水里
Agua, as in water.
可爱但是我来这儿并不是为了这个
Cute. But I wasn't here for cute.
我是因为收到定期缴费通知 才来这儿的
I was here 'cause I'd gotten a call for my regular fee.
4.99美元
$4.99.
我是个超级特工
I'm an ex-secret agent.
我叫朱尼·克兹
My name is Juni Cortez.
也是个私家侦探
And I'm a private detective.
A.P.I.私家侦探
A P.I. A private eye.
胶鞋
A gumshoe.
我知道为什么你家公园会没水了
I know why the water from your park is missing.
- 请说 - 冬天到了
- Pray tell. - It's winter.
他们在冬天关闭了公园
They shut down the park during the winter.
他们是谁?
Who's "they"?
真正拥有这座公园的人
The people who really own this park.
世道不好
Times are tough.
但是一个人必须去做 他该做的事儿
But a guy's gotta do what he's gotta do.
从拯救树上的猫…
From saving cats in trees...
到寻找遗失的玩具
...to finding lost toys,
帮助别人… 等等
to helping people... Hold on.
怎么?
Yeah?
欧斯找我?
The OSS is looking for me?
听着我已经不再是个特工了 我帮不了你
Look, I'm no longer an agent. I can't help you.
不管怎样那是你的问题
Whatever it is, it's your problem.
别烦我
Leave me alone!
我被欧斯公司骗了
I'd been burned by the agency. The OSS.
所以我一去不回头
So I left. No going back.
现在我处理我自己的任务
I handle my own assignments now.
规模小了一点
Smaller in scale.
我是在保留实力等着办大案
I was saving up for something big.
我排队站着…
I was standing in line
等候要买史上最大的模拟游戏
to buy my copy of the biggest virtual-reality game in history..
它在午夜才能玩非常刺激大概吧
It goes online at midnight. Pretty exciting, I suppose.
游戏结束
Game Over.
目前有史以来最大的电玩游戏
The biggest video game to ever be created, period.
这是个轰动世界性大事
This is a worldwide event.
只知道是个玩具制造商开发了这个游戏
The game was created by someone known only as the Toymaker,
这个人从不接受采访
who was once again unavailable for interviews.
但是现在有比游戏更重要的事儿
But there 's gotta be some things more important than games.
噢我们刚有提到凡是连过五关者…
Oh, and did we mention the surprises the Toymaker has in store
玩具制造商在店里所提供的惊喜吗?
for those of you that complete level five?
数不清的财富 玩具和奖品 超乎你的想像
Untold riches, toys, and prizes beyond your wildest dreams.
嘿 别插队 怪胎
Hey, no cutting in line, freak.
我没插队我就在这儿呢
I wasn't cutting. I was standing right here!
排最后面去
End of the line!
不用说
Needless to say,
我离开欧斯以后事情变得碍手碍脚
things have been pretty lame since I left the OSS.
事情即将变得更糟了
Things were about to get worse.
亲爱的朱尼
Dear Juni,
我作了点东西我想你会喜欢的
I was doing some work and thought you might like these.
迷你鲨
Miniaturized sharks.
记住他们还是会吃人的 所以千万别把你的手指放进鱼缸
Remember, they're still man-eaters, so don 't be poking your fingers in the bowl.
保重如果需要帮助的话我会赶来的
Take care. If you guys ever need anything, I'll be there.
罗梅罗
Romero.
拉尔夫回封感谢函 给罗梅罗吧
Ralph , write a thank-you note back to Romero.
乖一点各位别打架
Behave, you guys. No fighting.
- 你在干嘛？- 嗨 杰蒂
- Whatcha doin'? - Hi , Gerti.
我… 没干什么
I'm just doing nothing... again.
- 那是什么？- 墨西哥巧克力
- What's that? - Mexican chocolate.
- 你父母在哪儿？- 执行任务去了
- Where's your mom and dad? - On an assignment.
我的观点是 别参与家人的任务
It was my idea not to be part of the family business.
他们都出任务了 你姐姐也是吧?
They're all on missions. Your sister, too, huh?
自从去年圣诞节后我就没见过卡门了
I haven't seen Carmen since Christmas... Iast year.
你应该重新加入欧斯 可能真用的着你
You should join back up. The OSS could really use you.
- 是啊 利用我 - 我不是这个意思
- Yeah. Use me. - Not what I meant.
别计较过去的事了朱尼 看看我
Don't hold on to the past, Juni. Look at me.
9岁除了往上爬哪儿都去不了
9 years old and nowhere to go but up.
最值得依附的家 就是你出生的那个家
The only tribe worth belonging to is the one that you're born into.
是的你的家庭 要好好照顾你的家庭
Yeah, your family. It's good to take care of your family.
但记住一件事
But remember one thing.
每个人都是你的家人
Everyone's your family.
胡说
That makes no sense.
你好 朱尼
Hello, Juni.
总统先生
Mr. President.
叫我德夫林就行了
Oh, you can call me Devlin.
当你领导欧斯的时候 你不是就已经在治理这个国家了吗?
Weren't you already running the country when you were head of the OSS?
我正在治理着这个国家
I was running the country.
但是欧斯是个秘密组织 没人知道的
But since the OSS is a secret organization, no one knrw it.
我想要全世界都知道是由我掌权
I wanted the world to know that I was in charge.
所以我成了美国总统
So I became president of the United States.
全取决于你的喜好
It all depends upon your preference.
事实或者认知认知对我较有用
Reality or perception. Perception works for me.
哦 那我选事实
Well, I'm into reality.
事实是你一句话都不吭
And the reality is, nothing you can say
就让我重新加入欧斯 那是你打电话来的目的对吧?
will make me rejoin the OSS. That is why you called, isn't it?
欧斯需要你归队
The OSS needs you to return.
我已经退休了
I'm retired.
现在谁还活在认知当中呢?
Well, who's living in perception now?
事实是没有退休的
The fact is there is no retirement.
一旦为特工终身为特工
Once an agent, always an agent.
该是你成熟点复职的时候了
It's time for you to be a big boy and reinstate.
别无冒犯先生… 不
With all due respect, sir, no.
那就坐稳了因为事实是这样的
Then hold on to your seat, because here's the reality:
你姐姐失踪了
Your sister's missing.
带特工克兹到游戏理论部门
Taking Agent Cortez to Games and Theory.
是超级特工克兹
That's ex-Agent Cortez.
要知道那个人是个侦探
You know, that one's defective.
体型上有点问题
Something's wrong with the shape.
看看我们能不能收回那个
See if we can take that one back.
老天
Oh, man.
开始
We're on.
We're on!
你好 朱尼
Hello, Juni.
唐纳根 最近的表现好吗?
Donnagon. Been a good boy lately?
是的还行
Yes.
好非常好
Very, very good.
吉格斯夫人一定把你调教的很好
Mrs. Giggles must have straightened you out.
- 当然 - 你好 弗朗西丝卡
- I certainly did. - Hello, Francesca.
没错事实上她把我调教的非常好
Yeah, she worked me over pretty good, actually.
- 啊 - 亲爱的规矩些
- Aah. - Darling, behave.
对于那个叫"游戏结束"的电玩游戏 你了解多少?
What do you know about a video game called Game Over?
我知道世界上的每个孩子 都会登入里头玩
I know that just about every kid in the world is gonna sign on and play it.
有我们协助就不会了这游戏是个陷阱
Not if we can help it. The game is a trap.
一旦游戏开始
Once plugged into the game,
连父母亲都无法唤回孩子们的注意
parents won't even be able to get their children's attention.
还有什么新消息?
What else is new?
有次不同
This is different.
一旦你开始玩游戏 你的心智便属于玩具制造商
Once you get through the game, your mind belongs to the Toymaker.
就是这个游戏的开发者
The inventor of the game.
他想透过心智控制 来奴役全世界的青少年
He wants to enslave the world's youth with mind control.
控制了青少年也就控制了世界的未来
You control the youth, you control the future of the world.
你姐姐是个聪明的黑客
She's an ingenious hacker, your sister.
我们派她进去关闭这个游戏
We sent her inside to shut down the game.
但是…她消失了
But... she disappeared.
她怎么会在游戏中消失呢?
How can she disappear inside a game?
消失的不是她的肉体
She didn't physically.
事实上她的身体还在这幢大楼里
Actually, she's right here in the building.
卡门 卡门
Carmen! Carmen!
她听不见的她的心智还在游戏里呢
She can't hear you. Her mind's still in the game.
她已经到了第四关了 然后就失了踪
She got as far as level four, then nothing.
为什么让她单枪匹马到游戏里去?
Why would she even go in there without any backup?
因为她的最佳唯一人选 不肯回我们的电话
Because her first and only choice wouldn't answer our calls.
所以她决定一个人进去
So she decided to go alone.
现在你进去去找你的姐姐
Now, you go in. Find your sister.
在12小时之内帮助她关闭游戏
Help her shut down the game in 12 hours,
否则大家都完蛋
or it's game over for everyone.
你要加入我们吗?
Are you with us?
好的
OK.
那么就出发吧
Then let's go.
所以我必须关闭游戏 但不能放过玩具制造商?
So I have to shut down the game but not release the Toymaker?
没错如果让他跑了后果不堪设想
Exactly. It would be catastrophic if he escaped.
被关在虚拟世界中那么多年 他对我们恨之入骨
The T oymaker hates us for imprisoning him in cyberspace all these years.
- 为什么要把他关起来？- 天知道？陈年往事了
- What made you do that? - Who knows? It was years ago.
现在你得和大家一样从第一关打起
Now, you'll have to start on level one like everyone else.
到第四关找到你姐姐然后到达第五关
Find your sister on level four. Then proceed to level five.
- 那一关是攻不破的 - 第五关攻不破?
- Which is unwinnable. - Level five is unwinnable?
第五关也就是你关闭游戏程序的地方
Level five is where you shut down the game.
如果游戏程序没能关闭
If the game is not shut down,
你就会跟别人一样困在里头 等着玩具制造商统治世界
you'll stay trapped with everyone else when the Toymaker takes over the world.
把眼镜戴上
Put on these glasses,
你就会进入游戏世界了
and you'll enter the world of the game.
你会被送到卡门旁边一间无重力室
You're being sent into a zero-gravity chamber alongside Carmen.
那对你会比较有利
That should give you a competitive edge.
当你在游戏中东西会感觉很真实
When you're in the game, things will feel real.
是真实的?
Are they real?
祝你好运 朱尼
Good luck, Juni.
找到卡门 关闭游戏
Find Carmen. Shut down the game.
不论你做什么 千万别让玩具制造商出来
And whatever you do, don't let the Toymaker out.
电脑启动
Computer-generated.
低资源
Low-res!
卡门 卡门能听得见我说话吗?
Carmen. Carmen, can you hear me?
我是朱尼 你弟弟
It's Juni, your brother.
讨厌的蟾蜍
Pogo T oads!
嘿 去找你自己的座骑讨厌鬼
Hey! Get your own ride, creepo!
抱歉 我以为你是只蟾蜍呢
Sorry! I thought you were a toad.
你是新手吧?
Nrw player, huh?
对啊 新手
Yeah. New player.
那好就给你上上课
Well, here's a lesson you won't soon forget.
他怎么样了?
How is he?
脑电波正常
His brain waves are normal.
但他情况怎样?
But how is he?
摔下去了
Oh. He fell.
站起来
Stand up.
你摔落了三层
You fell three stories.
我还活着?
Aah. I survived?
不完全是那是你的生命值
Not exactly. That is your life count.
受重伤的话生命值会损失
After taking heavy damage, you lose a life.
到了零的时候会怎么样?
What happens when I hit zero?
游戏结束
Game over.
当你生命值为零的时候你就输了 不能重玩不能重新开始
When you run out of life, you lose. No replays. No restarts.
我的十二小时怎么回事？现在只剩四小时了
What happened to my 12 hours? I only have four now.
当你玩游戏的时候时间消耗很快的
Time flies when you're playing games.
太疯狂了
This is crazy.
动作最好快点
Better hurry.
你是谁?
So who are you?
我是朱尼·克兹 欧斯的超级特工
I'm Juni Cortez, ex-secret agent of the OSS.
我必须到第五关去
I need to get to level five.
我只剩几小时可以去阻止 玩具制造商控制世界了
But I only have a frw hours before the T oymaker takes over the world.
- 第五关？- 第五关是攻不破的
- Level five? - Level five is unwinnable.
我明白那点但是我得去拯救世界
I understand that. But I have to save the world.
雷兹这个人觉得他能到第五关
Rez, this person thinks he's level-five material.
我听见了
So I hear.
你们肯定是测试员
You guys must be beta testers.
朋友第一名才可以在这些 令人羡慕的数位山上自由走动的
One of the first allowed to roam free these coveted digital hills, my friend.
能帮你什么吗?
How can I offer service?
我叫雷兹
I'm Rez.
嗨 雷兹 说到拯救世界
Hi, Rez. Now, about saving the world.
如果有人能在第五关得到大奖
If anyone's gonna get to the great prize at level five,
肯定是咱们其中的一个
it's gonna be one of us.
不管怎样我想盗取密码
Whatever. I want cheat codes.
走后门 抄捷径什么的
Back-door entrances. Shortcuts. Anything.
我可以付你额外奖金
I can pay you with bonus packs.
任何形式的作弊 比如骗取密码骗过引导系统
Implementation of any form of hack code or cheat boost
都会导致游戏直接结束
will trigger an immediate game over
那就得永远待在游戏里了
and permanent evac from the game.
你的技术手册上这么说的
It's in your tech manual.
你必须按规则去玩
You have to play the game by the rules
否则什么也完成不了
or not at all.
那好吧
All right.
怎样才能以最快速度到第二关?
How do I get to level two as quickly as possible?
注意你的生命值
Lives are at stake. Please.
看见那个靶子了吗？打它
See that target? Hit it.
你会直接跳到月亮上去的
You'll bounce straight to the moon.
没错我建议用助跑开始
Yeah. I'd suggest a running start.
第二关是在月亮的背面
Level two is on the dark side of the moon.
到那儿的方法就是击打那个靶子 然后跳到月亮上
The way to get there is by hitting that target and bouncing to it.
这些游戏没什么真实性可言对吧?
Not a lot of realism in these games, is there?
估计不会再见到他了 我们走
Won't be seeing him anymore. Let's go.
竞争对手越少越好
Less competition, the better.
好极了
Oh, great.
欧斯发的信息要接收吗?
A message from the OSS. Do you accept?
好朱尼 我们无法再帮你了
OK, Juni, we can no longer be of assistance.
帮什么?
What assistance?
你多加了一条生命值
You do get one additional lifeline,
你可以选择现在使用还是晚点使用
which you can choose to use now or later.
现在 快点给我
Now! Give it to me now.
你可以从外面找个人来
You get to bring in any one person from the outside
帮你走完余下的路
to help you on your journey.
播放家人档案
Call up the family files.
自信 活力精通空手道
Assertive. Athletic. Knows karate.
聪明
Intelligent.
讲求策略
Strategic.
精通空手道
Knows karate.
等会儿回爷爷那儿去
Wait a minute. Go back to Grandpa.
优势:出众的智商
Pros: superior intellect.
劣势:残疾的身体
Cons: physically disabled.
他腰部以下瘫痪了足足30年
He's been paralyzed from the waist down for 30 years.
他的活力重新激发了出来
His energy force would have doubled back again ,
使他的臂膀 心脏 大脑 比常人强了两倍
making his arms, his heart, his brain twice as strong as a normal person.
- 先生你在想什么？- 我选爷爷
- What are you thinking, sir? - I choose Grandpa.
确认已选稍等
Selected. One moment.
那有些快了点
That was fast. Sort of.
爷爷
Grandpa!
朱尼
Juni!
我在哪儿?
Where am l?
一个由叫玩具制造商的疯子 操纵的电玩游戏中
In a video game run by a madman called the T oymaker.
玩具制造商在这儿?
The T oymaker is here?
你认识他?
You know him?
我搜捕他有30年了 朱尼
I've been hunting him down for 30 years, Juni.
- 你不该把我带到这儿来的 - 我需要你的帮助
- You shouldn't have brought me here. - I needed your help.
我们必须找到卡门然后关闭游戏
We have to find Carmen and shut down the game.
那是什么?
What is that?
某种加速器之类的吧
It's a power-up of some kind.
大支架
Mega Legs.
把它给我
Give it to me.
爷爷?
Grandpa?
你能走了
You can walk.
不只这一点朱尼
No, Juni.
我可以做的更多
Oh, I can do more than that.
爷爷?
Grandpa?
你去哪儿?
Where are you going?
别等我了朱尼我会追上你的
Don't wait for me, Juni. I'll catch up with you.
但是我们必须去找…
But we have to find...
卡门
Carmen.
瓦仑丁 我的老朋友
Valentin, my old friend.
你觉得这次你能追上我吗?
You think you'll catch me this time, don't you?
你能
you will.
噢 你能的
Oh, you will.
每样东西就定位
Everything falls into place.
每样东西都会
Everything falls.
一位新的参赛者 欢迎来到机械关
A courageous nrw contestant. Welcome to the Robocon.
我必须到第二关去
I need to get to level two.
你来错地方了
Well , you came to the wrong place.
这里是灾祸竞技场
This is the Arena of Misfortune.
要是想到第二关 你必须操纵机器打一场才行
T o get to level two, you're gonna have to battle a Mech.
那我该怎么做?
How do I do that?
你上去之后我会给你解释的
I'll explain it to you when you get up there.
嘿 到了
Hey, there.
到那儿去操控机器打一场
Just go out there in your Battle Mech and fight.
等会儿我跟谁对打?
Wait a minute. Who am I fighting?
她
Her.
别被打扁了我就可赢得额外点数
Don't get too trashed and I win bonus points.
右脚 左脚
Right foot, left foot.
右脚
Right foot. Oh!
这东西怎么操纵啊?
Oh! How do you work this thing?
我希望彼此光明正大来个机器决斗
OK, I want a good, clean robo fight.
不准打腰部以下不准打后脖
There will be no kidney punches, no rabbit punches,
不准戳眼和咬耳朵
no eye gouging or ear biting.
当然除非是逼不得已
Unless, of course, you can 't help yourself.
你好
Hi.
我叫朱尼
I' m Juni.
哦很抱歉
Oh , l' m sorry.
很抱歉不是故意的
I'm sorry. He didn't mean it.
真的真的
Really, really.
不 不 不
No. No, no, no!
拜托 不要
Please, no!
嗨 我叫德米雀
Hi. I'm Demetra.
救命
Help.
那一定很痛
Oh! That's gotta hurt.
我是胜利者
I'm the winner!
好耶
Whoo! Yes!
对一个不懂如何格斗的孩子来说
For a kid that doesn't know how to fight,
你肯定懂得如何格斗的
you sure know how to fight.
恭喜你衣服穿着吧
Congratulations. And keep the suit.
嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey!
嘿
Hey!
那么让我们再重来一遍如何?
So, let's go over this again, shall we?
没有失误 没有严重失误
So there's no mistake. So there's no gross error.
所以我们之间没有沟通不良问题
So there's no lack of communication amongst us.
我想要我们想要…
What I want, what we want...
我们想要什么来着?
What do we want?
我们在这星球上的时代已经结束了 该是属于年轻人的时候了
Our time on this planet is over. It belongs now to our youth.
除非我们控制住他们的思想
Not if we control their minds!
那样我们就可以重新开创这个世界 治愈它所有的疾病
We could start the world over again and cure it of its diseases.
我们可以重新来过
We could begin anrw.
忘掉那些可以做的吧 这是我们应该做的
Forget what we could do! It's what we should do!
我现在做的正确吗?
Am I doing the right thing?
不是正不正确的问题而是聪不聪明
It's not about the right thing. It's about the smart thing.
否则我们逃不出这儿
We won't escape this place otherwise.
当我说"我们要出去"的时候 是代表我们所有人说的
I speak for all of us when I say, "We want out!"
结局会证明这个方法的
The end justifies the means.
你掌握着孩子们的注意力
You have the children's attention.
问题是你在教他们什么?
The question is, what are you teaching them?
你们是谁?
Who are you people?
我们就是你
We are you.
请原谅请原谅
Forgive me. Forgive me.
我偶尔会忘记我的程式分身
I forget the extent of my programming powers from time to time.
有一阵子我真的相信你们存在
For a moment, I actually believed that you existed.
再见
Goodbye.
出去出去
Out, out, out.
Out, out.
这个幼稚的游戏很快会结束的
This childish game will soon be over.
真实的游戏即将开始
And then the real game will begin.
看看这个
Will you look at this?
拿好你的操纵杆各位 我想我们找到他了
Hold on to your joysticks, boys. I think we got him.
你就是"家伙"
You're the Guy.
你说我是谁?
I'm the who?
"家伙" 海报里的那个
The Guy. The guy from the poster.
那个人
That guy.
不等等
No. Wait a minute.
我只是在找我的姐姐 她在第四关的某个地方
I'm only looking for my sister. She's somrwhere on level four.
然后我要通过第五关
Then I'm heading out through level five.
这么说你能赢得比赛?
So you can win the game?
我想那是一个可以关闭它的方法
I guess that's one way of putting it.
你瞧根据技术手册上说
You see, according to the tech manual,
如果我们找到那个"家伙"…
if we find the Guy...
这"家伙"…
the Guy...
他会带领我们通过那个攻不破的关
he'll lead us through the unwinnable level.
只因为他一下子就过了机械关卡
Just 'cause he made it out of Robocon in one piece
并不意味着他就是这"家伙"啊
doesn't mean he's the Guy.
他是我见过第一位穿着能量装通过的
He's the first I've seen to make it out with the power suit.
得了吧这胆小鬼是个冒牌货
Man, give me a break. This wimp's a phony.
只有一个办法可以证明
There's only one way to find out.
大型赛车比赛
Mega Race.
游戏世界中最高速 最危险的比赛
The fastest, most dangerous race in the game world.
- 来吧 - 不等等
- Come on. - No. Wait.
我都告诉你我不是这"家伙"了
I already told you I'm not the Guy.
- 快走 - 好吧
- Go. - OK.
比赛马上就要开始了
The race will begin shortly.
选定自己的车辆
Claim your vehicle.
一定是在开玩笑
You got to be kidding.
这个比赛可以辨识出 你究竟是不是"家伙"
This race will tell us if you're the Guy.
如果是的话就可以和我们一块作伴
If you are, you can hang with us.
要是你不是阿诺德会把你撕碎的
But if you're a phony, Arnold will crush you.
我不是这"家伙"
I'm not the Guy.
到底要我说多少遍呢?
How many times do I have to say it?
比赛没有任何规则
There are no rules in this race,
不惜代价取胜便行
except win at any cost.
好吧
All right!
我们会尽全力去帮你的
We'll try to help you out... as much as we can.
比赛即将开始…开始
The race will begin... now.
一 二 三出发
One, two, three, go!
- 非常简单 - 朱尼按红色按钮
- Easy as pie. - Juni , push the red button.
那个写着"不准按"的按钮?
The one that says "Do not push"?
没错按下它它是个加速按钮
Yeah. Push it. It's a turbo boost.
- 你肯定？- 当然
- Are you sure? - Yeah.
嘿 雷兹 伸个援手吧
Hey, Rez, give me a hand!
嘿 伸只脚如何?
Hey, how about a foot?
换我开了 混蛋
My turn, sucker.
你应该会赢得比赛的 朱尼
You're supposed to be winning the race, Juni.
爷爷
Grandpa!
这是什么?
What is this?
手套
The glove!
抓住手套
Grab the glove.
手套
The glove!
抓另一辆车朱尼
Grab another bike, Juni!
最后一圈
Final stretch!
五… 四…
Five... four...
三… 二… 一
three... two... one.
坐钢圈的胜利者朱尼·克兹
Winner by a hubcap, Juni Cortez!
- 我觉得你就是他 - 我就知道
- I thought you were him. - I knrw it.
大概是吧
I guess you are.
听说你就是"家伙"
So, I hear you're the Guy.
绝对是
I am definitely the Guy.
- 现在想干嘛"家伙"？- 我得和我爷爷说两句
- So now what, Guy? - I have to go talk to my grandfather.
和谁?
To who?
我是说我得和…
I mean I must confer
和阿塔利世嘉任天堂的精灵说两句
with the Wizard of Atari-Sega-Nendo.
嗯 好的 太好了
Yeah. OK, cool.
恭喜你赢得了比赛
Congratulations. You won the race.
但现在他们认为我是某个重要人物 可以替他们赢得比赛
But now they think I'm some important guy who's going to win for them.
这对我们来说很好
For our purposes, that's very good.
他们可以带领我们更快到达第四关
They can lead us to level four more quickly,
那你就可以去找你姐姐了
so you can find your sister,
就可关闭游戏让一切恢复正常
so we can shut down the game and make things right.
那我就可以找到…
And so that I can find...
玩具制造商
the Toymaker.
我们不可接近玩具制造商的
We're not supposed to get near the Toymaker.
欧斯的规则上有说
So say the rules of the OSS,
我才不遵守呢
which I'm not following.
他很可能会跑掉我们不能冒那个险
He might escape. We can't risk that.
噢 不 朱尼
Oh, no, Juni.
我没打算让他跑掉
I don't plan on letting him go anywhere.
家伙
Guy!
这件事我们以后再说
We'll talk about this later.
好是这样的
OK. Here it is.
不该是我带你们到第五关
I'm not supposed to lead you to level five.
应该是你们带我去的呀
You're supposed to lead me there.
那你意思是说我们同心协力?
So you mean we work together?
精灵说只要我们同心协力就会胜利
The wizard said if we all work together, we all win.
靠我的力量
With my strength.
我的智慧
My brains.
我的酷
My cool.
我的直觉
My intuition.
好 所以说你是"家伙" 我们全指望你了
OK. So you're the Guy. We're all counting on you.
但是如果你害我们失败 或者你不是你所说那个人的话
But if you fail us or if you're not who you say you are,
这生命值计数器会比你 喊声"噢"还要快归零
this life counter will hit zero faster than you can say "oops."
一言为定
Deal.
首先我得去找我姐姐
First I got to find my sister.
去第四关吧各位
So level four, people.
行动
Move!
快点爷爷
Come on, Grandpa.
他干得不赖对吧?
He's doing good, huh? Huh?
没错他干得不错但这就是问题所在
Yeah, he's doing great, and that's the problem.
为什么?
Why?
他们唤醒了程式设计师
They've awoken the Programmerz.
什么?
What?
- 赶紧把他拉出来 - 太迟了
- Pull him out of there now. - Too late.
好的这太酷了
All right. This is cool.
我们马上就会到那儿的
We'll get there in no time.
这是什么?
What is this?
等会儿
Wait a minute.
程式设计师
The Programmerz.
谁是程式设计师?
Who are these Programmerz?
就是编写这个游戏程式的人
The brainiacs who wrote the book for the game.
这么说他们是为玩具制造商工作的了?
So, they work for the Toymaker, huh?
就是因为他们 你们才会在第一关找到我们的
Programmerz are the reason you found us on level one.
他们逮到弗朗西斯在 大型赛车比赛时候作弊
They caught Francis cheating during the Mega Race.
如果他们抓到我们的话 我们就得从第一关重新打起
They'll bounce us back to level one again if they catch us.
第一关？我可没有时间重打了
Level one? I don't have time for that.
散开
Spread out.
别散开 行不通的
Don't split up! It never works!
只要我们团结在一起…
If we just stick together...
好吧爷爷我想就剩你和我了
All right, Grandpa. I guess it's just you and me.
喂?
Hello?
爷爷?
Grandpa?
至少你该尝试表现的像"家伙"吧?
Can you at least try and act like you're the Guy?
你知道我的秘密?
You know my secret?
我见过真的"家伙"你不是他
I've seen the real Guy, and you're not him.
为什么程式设计师要追我们?
Why are Programmerz chasing us?
有人在游戏中作弊了
Someone's got a game cheat.
这是什么?
What's this?
游戏地图
A map to the game.
这是违反规则的
This is illegal.
你想不想找到你姐姐?
You want to find your sister or not?
把地图给我
Give me the map.
好了
OK.
我们现在位置在机器城
We're in Machine City.
直接穿过这儿的话就能够到达第四关
If we cut across here, we'll be able to reach level four.
卡门就在那里
Where Carmen is.
没错
Right.
然后如果抄近路穿过熔岩山的话
Then, if we cut through Lava Mountain,
我们就能到达不败关卡的关口了
we'll be right at the door of the unwinnable level.
抄近路很好这太棒了
Shortcuts. This is good. This is very good.
比赛作弊
Game cheats.
这不符合规定的
That's against the rules.
我们不得不让你们回到第一关去
We're gonna have to bounce you back to level one.
- 啊! - 你吓不了我们 他可"家伙"呢
- Aah! - You can't scare us. He's the Guy.
爷爷
Grandpa!
听见了吧 埃道格 "家伙"在呼叫他的爷爷
Listen to that, Edog. The Guy is calling his grandpa.
我好害怕 来抓我啊
I'm so scared. Come and get me, Gramps.
他能怎么样 逗我们开心吗?
What's he gonna do, drool on us?
你们为什么要找我孙子麻烦?
Why are you picking on my grandson?
为什么?
Why?
他们抓到了罗格斯和埃道格领导者
They got Logos and Edog, the leaders.
你们是程序设计师?
You are Programmerz?
来看看你们真正的长相吧
Let's see what you really look like, huh?
真是令人印象深刻
Very unimpressive.
电脑白痴
Computer nerds.
告诉我玩具制造商在哪儿?
Now tell me, where is the Toymaker?
爷爷…精灵放他们下来
Grandpa... uh, Wizard, put them down!
他很厉害呢
He's good.
这男孩战士非常非常厉害呢
The boy warrior is very, very good.
但他得继续前进
But he's got to keep going.
如果接下来的几关难度太大的话
We run the risk of discouraging him
会冒令他心灰意冷的险
if the next levels are too challenging.
但只有不断挑战
But only by seeking challenges
才有希望找出其中的佼佼者
can we hope to find the best in ourselves.
我们可以帮他吗?
Can we help him?
不行 这样违反游戏规则
No! It's against the rules of the game!
这不是游戏
This isn't a game.
这是人生
It's life!
不介意我自言自语吧?
I don't mind talking to myself.
但当你们把我排除在谈话之外时
But when you guys start to cut me out of the conversation,
就变得有点古怪了
that's when it gets a little strange.
没错我们需要更棒的人生
That's it. More life is what we need.
我们会送这小子一份礼物 生命值的礼物
We'll grant the boy a gift. The gift of life.
别担心"家伙"
Don't worry, Guy.
从这儿起我会保护你
From here on out, I'll protect you.
你还好吧"家伙"?
Are you all right, Guy?
嘿他找到加血包了
Hey. He found a life pack.
什么?
A what?
这很罕见啊
That's rare.
我以前从没看过加血包有这么近的
I've never seen one up close before.
我该怎么做?
What do I do?
用手将它捏碎就会获得生命值
Crush it in your hands. You'll gain life.
加多少?
How much?
全部
All depends.
我得到补充生命值了 德米雀
I got extra life, Demetra.
恭喜你 你最需要它了
Congratulations. You'll need it the most.
我要你收下
I want you to take it.
朱尼 我不能
Juni, I can't.
他知不知道那东西值多少?
Does he knowwhat that's worth?
他当然知道
Of course he does.
在机器人竞技场时我欠你的
I owed you from the Robot Arena.
而且我不希望你发生什么不测
Also, I don't want anything to happen to you.
多谢了
Thank you.
现在你们已进入第三关
You have now entered level three.
真希望我的家人能见见这奇妙的地方
I wish my family could see this amazing place.
阿诺德 你在游戏中是干什么的?
What are you doing in the game, Arnold?
事实上 我是靠测试员通行证进来的
Well, actually, I got in on a beta tester's visa.
我是来拿过第五关后的大奖
I'm here for the great prize behind level five.
它可以让我全家摆脱贫困
It'll save my family from poverty.
在第五关有什么东西呢?
But what waits for us in level five?
我是说全是真的吗？数不清的财宝?
I mean, is it all true? Untold riches?
阿诺德你要知道
Arnold, you should know
当我们到了关底的时候…
that when we reach the end of the game...
别别再说了
No. Don't tell me.
希望会是个惊喜
I want it to be a surprise.
一定是的
I'm sure it will be.
玩家们注意
Attention, gamers!
站到红线上
Stand on the red line.
选出你们中间最优秀的人
Choose your best player.
"家伙"! "家伙"是最优秀的
The Guy! The Guy's the best.
选出你们当中最强壮的人
Choose your strongest player.
那就是阿诺德了
That'd be Arnold.
适者生存
Survival of the fittest.
面向你们的对手
Face your opponent.
等等我 不要和阿诺德打
Wait a minute. I'm not fighting Arnold.
我也不想打倒朱尼
I don't want to crush Juni.
胜利者将和其他人一起进入第四关
The winner shall proceed with the others to level four.
失败者将会立即终止游戏
The loser shall be given an immediate game over
并且会被永远逐出游戏
and will be evacuated permanently from the game.
阿诺德 我得去救我姐姐
Arnold , I have to save my sister.
抱歉了 朱尼
I' m sorry, Juni.
但我得替我的家人着想
But I have my own family to think about.
我打不赢你的 阿诺德
I can't beat you , Arnold.
我知道
I know.
开始
Fight!
不是我特别支持谁
Not that I'm rooting for anyone in particular,
但那一招确实很酷
but that was a really cool move.
很高兴认识你 朱尼
Nice knowing you , Juni.
阿诺德 拜托
Arnold, please!
怎么回事?
What's going on?
你可以过关了
You've been tagged.
什么意思 我过关了?
What do you mean , I've been tagged?
有人和你换了位置
Someone has switched places with you.
不是我"家伙"
Not me, Guy.
德米雀 你在作什么?
Demetra, what are you doing?
你还得去找你姐姐呢 朱尼
You have to find your sister, Juni.
不 别去
Don't! Don't do it!
德米雀 不
Demetra, no!
开始
Fight!
- 不 - 啊!
- No! - Aah!
德米雀 游戏结束
Demetra, game over!
我甚至连她的伊眉儿都没有
I never even got her e-mail address.
别爱上游戏中的人朱尼
Don't fall in love with a game, Juni.
我们离开这儿吧
Let's get out of here.
很抱歉朱尼
Sorry, Juni.
我的家人
My family.
你引起了这么多的痛苦
You are causing so much pain.
只有我才可以阻止你
And only I can stop you.
因为我知道为什么你要做这些事…
For I knowwhy you do these things...
玩具制造商
Toymaker.
放马过来吧
Bring it on.
来找我啊 世界会真正付出代价的
Find me, and the world will truly pay the price.
我不得不建造出我的数位监狱
Here in my cyberprison I was forced to create.
现在我将会毁灭世界
Now I will destroy.
放了那女孩让她回游戏中去
Release the girl. Put her back in the game.
但是先生…
But, sir...
你有更好的解决办法 是吗?
Oh, you have a better solution, don't you?
你当然有了你们全都有
Of course you do. You all do.
那么告诉我真正答案是什么?
So tell me. What is the real answer?
- 我很好奇 - 复仇
- I'm so curious. - Revenge.
- 治愈 - 毁灭
- Healing. - Destruction!
- 爱 - 恨
- Love. - Hate.
你们全部又对了
Well, once again, you're all correct.
但也全部又错了
And once again, you're all incorrect.
游戏继续
On with the game.
你们现在正要进入第四关
You are now entering level four.
第四关？等等
Level four? Wait a minute.
卡门就在这一关
Carmen's on this level.
我用心灵感应找找看
I'll use telepathy.
可能够近了应该感应的到
We might be close enough that it'll work.
卡门 能听见我吗?
Carmen, can you hear me?
什么?
What?
这游戏会耍诈
This game plays tricks.
告诉我只有卡门会说的话
Tell me something only Carmen would say.
我有脚臭
My feet stink.
你听起来很近
You sound close.
是啊
I am.
我看见你带爷爷进了游戏里来
I see you brought Grandpa into the game.
我觉得这时候那么做是个好主意
I thought it was a good idea at the time.
朱尼
Juni!
玩具制造商就是三十年前 害得爷爷坐轮椅的人
The Toymaker's the guy who put Grandpa in the wheelchair
没错
Exactly.
如果爷爷想要报仇 玩具制造商就会被放出来
If Grandpa tries to take revenge, the Toymaker will break free.
他很强大的
He's that powerful.
那我们必须说服爷爷 复仇并不是解决问题的方法
Then we have to convince Grandpa that revenge is not the way to solve it.
好了"家伙"我们找到你的同伴了
OK, Guy. We found your pal.
我们现在到底要去哪儿？第五关在哪儿?
Now, where are we going, exactly? Where's level five?
首先别在这儿问问题
First of all, you don't ask the questions around here.
我知道在哪第二…
I do. Second of all...
- 我们要去熔岩山 - 我们要去?
- We're going to Lava Mountain. - We are?
越过那座山就是第五关的通道了
Beyond that is the passage to level five.
我可不这么想
I don't think so.
你突然变成游戏专家了
Oh, so suddenly you're the game expert.
我们跟"家伙"走
We're following the Guy.
朱尼 要知道我们不需要这些人跟着
You know, Juni, we don't need these guys following us.
我们要去的地方不需要
Not where we're going.
我答应他们会一起过关的
I promised them they could tag along.
瞧我就是这样 知道我们该去哪儿的 相信我
Look, this is how I knowwhere to go. Trust me.
熔岩山
Lava Mountain.
为什么每个电玩游戏中都有熔岩?
Why is it that every video game has lava in it?
技术上来说这说法不对
Technically, that's not true.
在《光环》游戏中就没有熔岩
There's no lava in Halo.
在《陨石》游戏中是熔浆
And in Metroid, it's molten magma.
别碰熔岩否则就游戏结束了
Can't touch the lava, or it's game over.
但是我还剩六格血
But I have six lives left.
那不重要一掉下去就输掉游戏了
Doesn't matter. You fall in, you lose.
各位游戏越来越难了
The game's getting tougher, guys.
这不可能
This is impossible.
你觉得怎样爷爷?
What do you think, Grandpa?
很难
Difficult.
走别条路吧跟我走各位
Let's go another way. Follow me, boys.
没道理啊
This doesn't make any sense.
我给了他们地图
I give them a map.
我给了他们那个女孩
I give them the girl.
他们还想要怎样?
What more do they want?
难道要我把他们带到关口那儿?
Can't I just lead them to the door?
不可能的先生 游戏人工智慧运作方式是…
Impossible, sir. The way the game's A.I. works is...
我知道我知道
I know. I know.
我自言自语不行吗?
Can I just talk to myself at least?
你在自言自语而我就是你
You are talking to yourself. I am you.
那么你 我…都闭嘴吧
Well, then, you, me, shut up.
好的
So be it.
我疯了吗?
Am I insane?
完全疯了
Completely.
他们走错路了
They're going the wrong way.
我得让他们到第五关
I have to drive them to level five.
派锅怪进去
Send in the Tinker Toys.
找另一条路这是个好主意
Finding another path. Now, this is good thinking.
她很厉害我们应该多听听她的意见
She's good. We should listen to her more often.
- 别站我旁边 - 好的
- Stay off my side. - OK.
这是什么?
What is this?
锅怪
Tinker Toys!
等等 熔岩和锅怪哪个比较糟?
Wait! What's worse, lava or Tinker T oys?
当然是锅怪
Definitely Tinker T oys.
卡门 我们该怎么办?
Carmen, what do we do?
冲浪啰 朱尼
Rip that wave, Juni.
他们在干嘛?
What are they doing?
他们偏离道路了
They're straying from the path.
玩具制造商一定是想把他们 引入他的老巢里
The T oymaker must be pushing them towards his lair.
但为什么呢？他能获得什么…
But why? What could he gain from...
查查看爷爷和玩具制造商之间 是否有所关连性
Check if there's a connection between the grandfather and the Toymaker.
快点各位
Hurry, people!
屏幕上显示出来了
It's coming on-screen.
化友为敌
Comrades turned enemies.
爷爷想把玩具制造商从游戏里放出来
Grandpa's gonna break the Toymaker out of the game.
阻止他们
Stop them.
搅动熔岩波浪大一点
Stir the lava. Bigger waves.
熔岩怪兽随便什么都行
Lava monsters. Anything.
我们得给他们创造些障碍物
We have to create obstacles for them.
快点
Come on!
我们必须淹死他们
We have to drown them.
那他们游戏就会结束 会被逐出游戏
They'll get a game over and be evacuated from the game.
我们不能冒玩具制造商被放出来的险
We can't risk letting the Toymaker out.
动手吧
Do it.
这是新增的
This is nrw.
朱尼
Juni!
卡门
Carmen!
弗朗西斯
Francis!
阿诺德
Arnold!
爷爷
Grandpa!
我
Me.
他们到哪儿去了?
Where are they?
掉进去了
They fell in.
我知道但应该显示游戏结束的啊
I know, but they should have gotten a game over.
事实上他们应该回到这儿
They should be back here, actually.
熔岩是冷的
The lava. It's cold.
这边朱尼这边 我们找到下一关的入口了
This way, Juni. This way. We found a door to the next level.
快点
Come on.
我还以为我完蛋了
I thought I was a goner.
我看到我的点数 在我眼前闪来闪去的
I saw all my points flashing away before my eyes.
我只听到我爸在说 "阿诺德你搞砸了"
All I could hear was my father saying , "You blrw it, Arnold."
"你没有数不清的财宝了"
"No untold riches for you."
爷爷呢?
Where's Grandpa?
不知道可是他刚刚还在这儿的
I don't know. But he was here.
这是不是他盔甲上的东西?
Isn't this a piece of his armor?
卡门 是通道帮忙打开它
Carmen, it's a passage. Help me open it.
红旗 雷兹
Red flag, Rez.
我们得谈谈这位"家伙"高度敏感问题
We have to talk about the Guy. Highly sensitive.
他怎么了?
What about him?
我一直复习我的技术手册
I've been rereading my tech manual.
里面说到游戏中有一个骗子
It speaks of a deceiver within the game,
会误导我们到一个万劫不复之地
who will mislead you down a path where no one will survive.
我觉得朱尼就是这个骗子
I think Juni's the deceiver.
你有何建议?
What do you suggest?
我们得除掉他 不然就有输掉游戏的危险
We'll have to get rid of him or risk losing the game.
那他姐姐怎么办?
What about his sister?
一样
Her too.
- 我们还剩多少时间？- 五分钟
- How much time do we have left? - Five minutes.
五分钟里会发生什么呢?
What happens in five minutes?
这地方会挤满了世界各地来的玩家
This place gets flooded with players from around the world.
好极了有的竞争了
Oh, great. Competition.
玩具制造商会控制他们的心智
The Toymaker will take over their minds.
所以我们得关闭游戏
That's why we have to shut down the game.
- 嘘卡门 - 她在说什么呢?
- Sh, Carmen! - What is she talking about?
你还没告诉他们吗?
You didn't tell them yet, did you?
我正想说呢
I was getting around to it.
骗子
Deceivers.
第五关另一边是什么?
What about the other side of level five?
没有什么另一边 你们会被囚禁在这游戏里
There is no other side. You'll be imprisoned in the game.
游戏结束
Game over.
我们不会让你们关闭游戏的
We're not letting you shut down this game.
你们会明白计数器倒数会有多快
You're gonna see how fast that counter can count backwards.
那你得先过我这关游戏小子
You have to go through me first, game boy.
不听我说我是"家伙"
Now, listen to me. I'm the Guy.
别再说你是"家伙"了
Stop saying you're the Guy.
我们都知道你不是
We all know that you're not the Guy.
他不是"家伙"
He's not the Guy.
我才是
I am.
你是?
And you are?
我是"家伙"
I'm the Guy.
真正的"家伙"
The real Guy.
而且我说我们进去
And I say we go in,
战胜这号称不败关卡到达另一边
beat this unwinnable level, and get to the other side,
那儿有数不尽的财宝 和十个城池大的土地等着我们呢
where untold riches and a bounty fit for 10 kings awaits us.
我就知道
I knrw it.
好了他绝对是"家伙"
Now, he's definitely the Guy.
但它是攻不破的
But it's unwinnable.
没有什么是攻不破的
Nothing is unwinnable
只要我们齐心协力 同仇敌忾
if we join together and battle as one.
发挥各人的力量
We play on each other's strengths
弥补彼此的弱点
and help cover each other's weaknesses.
就能达成任何事情
We can accomplish anything.
我们会达成所有事情的
And we will accomplish everything.
但首先我们要去战胜这道攻不破的关
But first let's go whip this unwinnable level
让它看看谁才是老大
and show it who's boss.
你们要加入吗?
Are you with me?
要
Yeah!
站到旁边去
Stand aside.
小意思
Cake.
天哪
Oh, my.
"家伙"
Guy!
好吧 你又是"家伙"了
OK. You're the Guy again.
带我们通过这儿吧朱尼
Get us through this, Juni.
但是我…
But l...
德米雀
Demetra!
朱尼 快点
Juni, quickly!
我找到关闭游戏的开关了
I found the switch to shut down the game.
而且我还找到了出口
I also found the exit portal.
我们马上都能从这儿出去了
We can all get out of here right now.
你怎么还活着?
How did you survive?
游戏出了点小故障 我也不太清楚
There was a glitch in the game. I don't know.
朱尼她是谁?
Juni, who is this?
她是德米雀 我女朋友
This is Demetra, my girlf...
我的朋友 不她是我的…
My friend. No, she's my...
我是他女朋友你又是谁?
I'm his girlfriend. Who are you?
我是他姐姐
I'm his sister.
她给了我到这儿的地图
She gave me the map. The map that got us here.
朱尼她不是真人
Juni, she's not real.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
我一直帮忙 朱尼获胜
I've been helping Juni win the game.
你又做了些什么?
What have you been doing?
就只会扮演囚犯
Playing prisoner. That's what.
她陷害了你朱尼她陷害我们所有人
She set you up, Juni. She set us all up.
我…朱尼她撒谎
I... Juni, she's lying.
她是玩具制造商的囚犯
She's been the Toymaker's prisoner.
据我们所知她可能被洗了脑
She could be brainwashed, for all we know.
你到底想不想赢得比赛?
Do you want to win this game or not?
这一关之所以攻不破 就是因为她
She's the reason this level's unwinnable.
她就是骗子
She's the deceiver.
为什么?
Why?
很抱歉 朱尼
I'm sorry, Juni.
但我的程式就是这么设计的
But it's in my programming.
恭喜
Congratulations!
你们已到达游戏的关底 你们赢了
You've made it to the end of the game! You won!
无尽的财宝都是你们的了
Untold riches for all of you!
而你们的奖品就是…待在这里
And your prize is you get to stay... here.
欢迎来到游戏中
Welcome to the game.
朱尼这边
Juni , this way.
这是出口
This is the way out.
大家快点
All of you , quickly!
等等 我们得去关闭游戏
Wait! We have to shut down the game.
我已经关了开关就在那儿
I already did. The switch is right there.
- 你确定？- 当然当然
- Are you sure? - Yes, yes.
快点走吧快点
Go. Quickly, quickly.
爷爷快跑
Run, Grandpa!
你走吧我来顶着
Go. I'll hold it open.
快点走
Go now!
德米雀
Demetra.
我无法永远按住的朱尼
I can't hold it open forever, Juni.
成功了
We made it.
这是我们的伊眉儿地址以防万一
Here's our e-mail addresses. Just in case.
妙极了
Terrific.
爷爷你真棒
You're awesome, Grandpa.
你对付那些锅怪的样子
The way you took on those Tinker Toys.
你是最酷的
You're the coolest.
万分感谢"家伙"
Thanks for everything, Guy.
真的有点吧
It was real. Sort of.
谢啦"家伙"
Thanks a lot, Guy.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
你不想离开吗?
You don't want to leave, do you?
我怎能回去呢朱尼?
How can I go back, Juni?
在这儿我能走能跑
In here, I can walk. I can run.
而且你把我当作一个超级大英雄
And you look at me like I'm some kind of superhero.
你本来就是
You are.
对我来说在外面的真实世界里
Out there in the real world, to me.
你也是
You are.
好吧 朱尼
All right, Juni.
我会回去的只要…
I shall go back if...
只要你答应我即使我坐在轮椅上
if you promise me that even though I'll be in a wheelchair,
你还一样能像现在这样看待我的话
that you will look at me no differently than you are now.
因为在我内心朱尼在内心里 我想要这个样子
Because on the inside, Juni, on the inside, I feel like this.
我答应爷爷
I promise, Grandpa.
该走了
Time to go.
借过麻烦借过一下
Coming through. Coming through, please.
那些电玩游戏就是视觉杀手吧孩子?
Those video games are killers on the eyes, huh, kid?
特工克兹 我们要拿走
Agent Cortez, we'll take it from here.
我的孙子会处理的
My grandson will handle this.
别碰这可是柯林斯皮呢
Don't touch. This is Corinthian leather.
好的
OK.
再说一遍 你们是怎么关闭游戏的
So tell me again how you shut off the game.
事实上我不太清楚是否关闭了
I don't know if we shut it down, exactly.
我们扳动了开关 好像起作用了
We hit a switch, and it seemed to work.
是起作用了 游戏被关闭了
Oh, it worked. The game's down.
我们只是得弄清楚 做的对不对
We just need to make sure we did this correctly.
事实上是爷爷扳动的开关
Actually, Grandpa hit the switch.
克兹这些是在游戏中 和你一块的孩子吗?
Cortez, are these the boys that were in the game with you?
我们透过伊眉儿找到了他们
We tracked them through their e-mail addresses.
是他们没错 他们不懂得…
Yeah, that's them. They wouldn't know anything about...
嘿 等等
Hey, wait a second.
聪明的弗朗西斯…
What happened to Francis the Brain,
强壮的阿诺德和超酷先生呢?
Arnold the Strong, and Mr. Cool?
现实世界中我没那么聪明
Well, in the real world, I'm not that smart.
我也不强壮
I'm not strong.
我也不酷
I'm not cool.
真相是残酷的
Reality check.
那么现实世界中你是谁呢?
So who are you out here in the real world?
超级特工克兹我们需要你
Special Agent Cortez, we need you.
我只是朱尼·克兹
I'm just Juni Cortez.
说吧爷爷你到底扳了哪个开关?
Let's have it, Grandpa. What switch did you hit exactly?
那儿有两个开关并排的
There were two switches side by side.
一个用来关闭游戏
One switch shuts down the game.
但另一个是释放玩具制造商
But the other releases the Toymaker.
哪个白痴设计的?
Who was the idiot who designed that?
你是不是不小心释放了玩具制造商?
Did you free the T oymaker by accident?
我是释放了玩具制造商但不是不小心
Oh, I freed the T oymaker. But it was no accident.
你想不想阻止这个游戏?
Do you want to stop the game?
那么你就必须打败玩具制造商 这是唯一的办法
Then you must defeat the T oymaker. It's the only way.
你这个疯老头
You crazy old man!
你知道你做了什么吗?
Do you know what you've done?
爷爷复仇不能解决问题的
Grandpa, revenge doesn't solve anything.
你相信我吗？你们所有人都相信我吗?
Will you trust me? You of all people?
总统先生传来的讯息
A message from the president.
他想干嘛?
Oh, what does he want?
我要回来和他们算帐
I'm coming back to settle the score.
因为他们监禁了我
For imprisoning me.
利用了我
For using me.
德夫林陷害我们的?
Devlin set us up?
不是德夫林
It's not Devlin.
我只想要纠正错误
All I wanted to do was right the wrongs.
开始一个新的世界
Start over a new world.
一个新的机会
A new chance,
每个人都能得到第二次机会的
where every.one would get a second chance!
但是我没有
But no.
所以现在我要把游戏带到下一关去
So now I'm taking this to the next level!
地图显示有地震活动发生
Seismic activity off the map!
地震
Earthquake!
龙卷风
T ornado!
飓风
Hurricane!
卡门 快走
Carmen , let's go!
诸位别紧张
Everybody, relax!
快点 赶紧把眼镜戴上
Quick! Put your glasses on.
只有这样你才能看清真正发生了什么
It's the only way you can see what's really happening.
游戏已经进入到真实世界中了
The game has entered the real world.
这种情况下只能做一件事
There's only one thing to do in a situation like this.
什么事?
What?
给家里打电话召集全家人
Call in the family. Calling all Cortezes.
没错没错
This is it. This is it.
没错
This is it.
我们期待已久的一刻到了
The moment we've been waiting for.
很好
Yes.
谁都不准动谁都不准动
Nobody move. Nobody move!
不许碰那个脑第五脑
Nobody touch the brain. The fifth brain.
这是历史性的一刻
This is a historic moment.
可能…
Probably the...
可能最重要的是…
Probably the most important...
不
No.
这是我一生中最重要的时刻
This is the most important moment of my life.
现在没人会打扰我了
No one can disturb me now.
我必须启动大脑
I must activate the brain.
就是现在
Now.
克兹先生?
Mr. Cortez?
你的孩子来电情况有点紧急
Your children called. Some sort of emergency.
我是他们的叔叔
Well, I'm their uncle.
(爸爸)
爸爸你得戴上这个来看
Dad, you need these to see.
眼镜快戴上
Glasses, quick!
来了
Incoming.
(妈妈)
(奶奶)
(大伯)
这不太容易
This won't be easy.
来踢点金属吧
Let's kick some metal.
其他人呢?
What about all the other ones?
我们需要更多援助我们家族不够庞大
We need more help. Our family isn't big enough.
记住一件事大家都是你的家人
Remember one thing. Everyone's your family.
呼叫…所有人
Calling... everyone.
我们来拯救今天吧
We're here to save the day.
小喽啰
Floop and Minion!
机器人小孩
Robot children!
把它们拆了
Take 'em down!
牛仔帅哥
Dinky Winks!
有人打电话给牛仔我吗?
Somebody ring the Dinkster?
你会教我的主题公园增色不少
You're gonna make a nice addition to my theme park.
伙计你完了 完了
Game over for you, pal. Game over!
有人打电话要单挑吗?
Somebody call in a loon?
抱歉 罗梅罗 只剩下这付眼镜了
Sorry, Romero, this is the only pair we had left.
有点破损
They're a little broken.
挺好的
They're perfect.
进攻 史波奇
Charge, Sporky!
爸爸宰了它
Brand him, Daddy.
谢谢小牛仔
Thanks, Little Dink.
加利·吉格斯?
Gary Giggles?
- 什么事？- 卡门·克兹
- Yeah? - Carmen Cortez.
我需要你立刻来帮我
I need your help right away.
这就去
I'm there.
我来了
I'm here.
帮帮我
Give me a hand.
- 呃! - 多谢了
- Unh! - Thanks.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
谢谢你杰蒂
Thank you, Gerti.
还有一个
There's still one more.
不可能
That's impossible.
得有个人爬上去
Someone has to go up there.
手动关掉它
And shut it down manually.
这是唯一的办法
It's the only way.
可是谁会去呢?
But who?
我准备好了
I'm ready.
我非去不可
It must be done.
不爷爷
Grandpa, no!
让他去吧这事注定得让他来做
Let him go. Your grandfather has to do this.
谢谢你把我放了 瓦伦丁 但是太迟了
Thank you for freeing me, Valentin, but it's too late.
谁也阻止不了我就算你也不行
Nothing can stop me. Not even you.
没错只有你能做到
That's true. Only you can do that.
你出卖了我们
You double-crossed us.
特工组织 你的同事还有我
The agency, your fellow agents, and me.
你的错误让我赔上一双腿
Your mistake cost me my legs.
像那种错误
Well, a mistake like that
只会把人推入更黑暗的深渊
could only push someone further into the dark.
的确如此
And it has.
看看现在的你
Look at you now.
在游戏世界中我把腿还给了你
I gave you back your legs in the game.
是为了你才那么做的
I did that for you.
让我告诉你我一生中错过的事吧
Let me tell you all the things I've missed in my life
因为你导致的意外事故
because of the accident you caused.
我不能和妻子一起在海滩散步
I can't walk on the beach with my wife.
我错过了我女儿的出生
I missed my daughter's birth.
和她的婚礼
And wedding.
还要我继续说下去吗?
Shall I continue?
爷爷
Grandpa.
不
Don't.
现在让我告诉你伴随而来的好处吧
Now let me tell you all the good things that came of it.
谦虚
Humility.
充满灵性
Spirituality.
谅解别人
Understanding.
这些年来你一直生活在畏惧我之中
You've been living in fear of me all these years.
但我只好一直寻找你
But I've only been searching for you
我才能对你说"我原谅你"
so I could tell you that I forgive you.
我只有作梦才会听到你说那样的话
I've only dreamed I would hear you say something like that.
现在问题是你能原谅你自己吗?
Now the question is, can you forgive yourself?
犹未晚也塞巴斯汀
It's never too late, Sebastian.
慢慢来慢慢做决定
Take your time. Take your time to decide.
我们还有大约十秒钟时间
We have about 10 seconds.
游戏…
Game...
结束了
over.
朱尼快离开那儿
Juni, get out of there!
爷爷
Grandpa!
等等
So, wait a minute.
谁赢了?
Who won?
不在于你赢还是输
It's not whether you win or lose.
在于你怎么玩这个游戏
It's how you play the game.
敬家人
To family.
- 敬家人 - 敬家人
- To family. - To family.
敬家人
To family.
- 敬家人 - 敬家人
- To family. - To family.
敬家人
To family.
- 家人 - 家人
- Family. - Familia.
- 敬家人 - 敬家人
- To family. - To family.
敬家人
To family.
放吧
And break!